Julian Beard

Software Engineer

(517) 626.4000 · badjab326@gmail.com · Murrieta, CA · julianbeard.codes · in/Julian-A-Beard · github.com/badjab326

Software engineer with nearly ten years in various team based, customer facing positions, and gained an extensive repertoire of communication, team building and resource management skills.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python | Libraries and Frameworks - React, Node.js, Express.js, Django, EJS Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose | Other - RESTful Routing JSON, Docker, AWS S3

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Idoona, Full-Stack Software Engineer | Bremen, Germany

Sep. 2022 - Present

- Plan architecture for new software projects, determining appropriate tech stack and MVP outline.
- Work with both frontend and backend technologies to develop a full-stack application based on client input.
- Use Mongo, Express, React, Node (MERN) and Sanity CMS to build and maintain client scale applications.
- Engineered user-focused survey tool making use of Government supplied data.

Alaska Airlines, Flight Attendant | Los Angeles, CA

Oct. 2017 - May 2022

- Enforced time management skills to work under tight time constraints to deliver optimal and safe service.
- Used strong communication and team management skills to work with highly diverse groups of people.
- Exerted patience and flexibility with adapting to constant changes in both the industry, and individual flights.
- Consistently learned and incorporated new skills and safety procedures into my workflow as needed.
- Handled secure information with care and confidence.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

2022 - Present

What2Play

- Built from the ground up using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Ajax.
- Utilized an API to retrieve photos and information of random video games based on user preferences.
- Styled using flexbox, custom fonts and manually edited backgrounds and designed with mobile browsers in mind via responsive design.

Avatar Yearbook

- Worked as Lead Backend Dev on a multi-page, create, read, update, delete (CRUD) digital yearbook for bootcamp graduates
- Used React. is to serve the front-end with Javascript methods and functions.
- Worked with an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend leveraging restful design, all CRUD operations, and testing with Postman.
- Served the backend of the application using Express methods and functions utilizing MongoDB database management.
- Added Backend user authentication/authorization using Google Firebase.

Gym Planner

- Produced app designed to give users the ability to digitally plan, track and optimize their workouts.
- Constructed with Python, Django, Materialize CSS and PostgreSQL.
- Implemented full user authentication and authorization, as well as admin functionality.
- Modeled with MVT architecture, managed deployment pipeline with use of Heroku.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

April 2022 - July 2022

Completed an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies, including development of multiple individual and group projects

COURSERA | REMOTE

Meta Full-Stack Engineering

July 2022-Oct 2022

Certified in multiple Software Engineering courses offered and sponsored by Meta Introduction to Front-End Development

- HTML and CSS in depth
- Programming with JavaScript
- React Basics

- Introduction to Back-End Development
- Version Control
- Programming in Python